Register of the Lawrence Dennis Papers, 1921-1975
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1931-1975
  - Books, 1940-1969 (Box 7)
    - Unpublished, fragmentary manuscripts, c. 1950's
      - Untitled (#2): Refers to patterns of error in analysis of U.S.-international relations, c. 1954
        - Why We are Losing Out to the Reds: Error., Three drafts: two original typescripts; one carbon copy (Folder 19)
        - We Need a New Foreign Policy to Escape WW III., One typescript carbon copy (Folder 20)
    - Operational Thinking For Survival, 1969 (Box 8)
      - General
        - Contract and copyright, 1968-1969 (Folder 1)
        - Financial statements, 1969-1975 (Folder 2)
      - Fragments. Carbon copies and original typescripts (Folder 3)
      - Draft #1: as sent to publisher. Missing chapters 17-21. Typescript carbon copy
        - Table of Contents (Folder 4)
        - Introduction: The Situation
        - 1. Survival the Big Issue. (Folder 5)
        - 2. Survival Comes Before Reform or Progress. (Folder 6)
        - 3. Four Great Challenges of the 20th Century. (Folder 7)
        - 4. The Underconsumption Challenge. (Folder 8)
        - 5. Only World War II Ended the Depression. (Folder 9)
        - 6. Operational Thinking About War. (Folder 10)
        - 7. The Revolt of the Masses and Population Increase. (Folder 11)
        - 8. Operational Thinking About Interest Conflicts and War. (Folder 12)
        - 9. Interest Conflicts Over Not Under Law. (Folder 13)
        - 10. Law as a Weapon. (Folder 14)
        - 11. Getting or Averting Results Not Applying Laws. (Folder 15)
        - 12. Finding a Viable Alternative to War and Communism The Problem. (Folder 16)
        - 13. Tolerance for Survival. (Folder 17)
        - 14. Collective Security and Interdependence versus Independence. (Folder 18)
        - 15. Limiting, Not Preventing, War, the Problem. (Folder 19)
        - 22. Semantic Awareness an Essential for Survival. (Folder 20)
        - 23. Operational Thinking v. Any Monistic Solution. (Folder 21)
        - 24. Is the 'New Economics' a Success or a Failure? (Folder 22)
        - Appendix I: The Wars of England, France and the United States Since 1775 (Folder 23)
      - Draft #2: as edited by publisher. Typescript original
        - Introduction (Folder 24)
        - Chapters 1-8 (Folder 25-32)
        - Chapters 9-15 (Box 9, Folder 1-7)
        - 16. Change by Limited or Unlimited War. (Folder 8)
        - 17. Modern War Must Be Socialistic. (Folder 9)
        - 18. Operational Thinking About Big War Debt. (Folder 10)
        - 19. Operational Thinking About Big Deflationary Debt Retirement. (Folder 11)
        - 20. Must the Post-World War II Inflation End in a Collapse? (Folder 12)
        - 21. 'Money--Master or Means?' (Folder 13)
        - Chapter 22 (Folder 14)
        - Chapter 23 (Folder 15)
        - Appendix I: formerly chapter 24 (Folder 16)
        - Appendix II: formerly appendix I (Folder 17)
      - Galleys, c. 1969 (Folder 18-19)
      - Proofs, c. 1969
        - Introduction-Chapter 8 (Folder 20)
        - Chapters 9-18 (Folder 21)
        - Chapter 19-Appendix II; book jacket (Folder 22)
      - Promotional material, 1969 (Folder 23)
      - Reviews, 1969 (Folder 24)
        - List of review copies sent
        - Schuman, Frederick L. Reflections of a Pragmatist. Reprinted from The Nation, 1969 Dec. 8.
- WEEKLY FOREIGN LETTER, 1938 June 30-1942 July 9
  - #1-12, 1938 June 30-1938 Sept. 15 (#7 missing) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - #13-26, 1938 Sept. 22-1938 Dec. 22-23 (Folder 2)
  - #27-38, 1938 Dec. 29-1939 April 20 (2/17/39: first issue with Dennis) (Folder 3)
  - #39-48, 1939 April 27-1939 June 29 (Folder 4)
  - #49-57, 1939 July 6-1939 Aug. 31 (#56 missing) (Folder 5)
  - #58-66, 1939 Sept. 7-1939 Nov. 2 (Folder 6)
  - #67-79, 1939 Nov. 9-1940 Feb. 1 (Folder 7)
  - #80-89, 1940 Feb. 8-1940 April 11 (#83 missing) (Folder 8)
  - #90-104, 1940 April 18-1940 July 25 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - #105-117, 1940 Aug. 1-1940 Oct. 24 (Folder 2)
  - #118-134, 1940 Oct. 31-1941 Feb. 20 (Folder 3)
  - #135-148, 1941 Feb. 27-1941 May 29 (Folder 4)
  - #149-167, 1941 June 5-1941 Oct. 9 (Folder 5)
  - #168-183, 1941 Oct. 16-1942 Jan. 29 (Folder 6)
  - #184-194, 1942 Feb. 5-1942 April 16 (Folder 7)
  - #195-206, 1942 April 23-1942 July 9 (Folder 8)
- APPEAL TO REASON, 1946 March 30-1972 Aug. 20
  - Unidentified draft copy, c. early 1950's. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - #1-17, 1946 March 30-1946 July 20
  - #18-38, 1946 July 27-1946 Dec. 14 (#24, #25 missing) (Folder 2)
  - #39-53, 1946 Dec. 21-1947 March 29 (Folder 3)
  - #54-70, 1947 April 5-1947 July 26 (#56 missing) (Folder 4)
  - #71-83, 1947 Aug. 3-1947 Oct. 25 (Folder 5)
  - #84-101, 1947 Nov. 1-1948 Feb. 28 (Folder 6)
  - #102-118, 1948 March 6-1948 June 26 (Folder 7)
  - #119-136, 1948 July 3-1948 Oct. 31 (Folder 8)
  - #137-157, 1948 Nov. 6-1949 March 26 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - #158-175, 1949 April 2-July 30 (#172 missing) (Folder 2)
  - #176-218, 1949 Aug. 6-1950 May 27 (#184-209 missing) (Folder 3)
  - #219-234, 1950 June 3-1950 Sept. 16 (Folder 4)
  - #235-249, 1950 Sept. 23-1950 Dec. 30 (Folder 5)
  - #250-266, 1951 Jan. 1-1951 April 28 (Folder 6)
  - #267-283, 1951 May 5-1951 Aug. 25 (#272 missing) (Folder 7)
  - #284-301, 1951 Sept. 1-1951 Dec. 29 (Folder 8)
  - #302-325, 1952 Jan. 5-1952 June 14 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - #330-344, 1952 July 19-1952 Oct. 25 (#326-329 missing) (Folder 2)
  - #345-362, 1952 Nov. 1-1953 Feb. 28 (Folder 3)
  - #363-379, 1953 March 7-1953 June 27 (Folder 4)
  - #380-405, 1953 July 4-1953 Dec. 26 (Folder 5)
  - #406-422, 1954 Jan. 1-1954 April 24 (Folder 6)
  - #423-436, 1954 May 1-1954 July 31 (Folder 7)
  - #437-449, 1954 Aug. 7-1954 Oct. 30 (Folder 8)
  - #450-462, 1954 Nov. 6-1955 Jan. 29 (Folder 9)
  - #463-475, 1955 Feb. 5-1955 April 30 (Folder 10)
  - #476-488, 1955 May 7-1955 July 30 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - #489-501, 1955 Aug. 6-1955 Dec. 29 (#500 missing) (Folder 2)
  - #502-514, 1955 Nov. 5-1956 Jan. 28 (#506 missing) (Folder 3)
  - #515-527, 1956 Feb. 5-1956 April 28 (Folder 4)
  - #528-540, 1956 May 5-1956 July 28 (Folder 5)
  - #541-557, 1956 Aug. 4-1956 Nov. 24 (Folder 6)
  - #558-569, 1956 Dec. 1-1957 Feb. 16 (#568-569 include pre-publication draft) (Folder 7)
  - #570-575, 1957 Feb. 23-1957 March 30 (#570-575 include pre-publication draft) (Folder 8)
  - #576-591, 1957 April 6-1957 July 20 (Folder 9)
  - #592-605, 1957 July 27-1957 Oct. 26 (Folder 10)
  - #606-623, 1957 Nov. 2-1958 March 29 (#620 missing) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - #624-640, 1958 April 12-1958 Nov. 22 (Folder 2)
  - #641-653, 1958 Dec. 6-1959 May 23 (#652 includes pre-publication draft) (Folder 3)
  - #654-668, 1959 June 6-1959 Dec. 19 (Folder 4)
  - #669-681, 1960 Jan. 2-1960 June 18 (Folder 5)
  - #682-695, 1960 July 2-1960 Dec. 31 (Folder 6)
  - #696-710, 1961 Jan. 4-1961 July 29 (Folder 7)
  - #711-721, 1961 Aug. 12-1961 Dec. 30 (Folder 8)
  - #722-736, 1962 Jan. 13-1962 July 28 (Folder 9)
  - #737-751, 1962 Aug. 11-1963 Feb. 23 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - #752-766, 1963 March 9-1963 Sept. 21 (Folder 2)
  - #767-782, 1963 Oct. 5-1964 May 2 (Folder 3)
  - #783-798, 1964 May 16-1965 Feb. 20 (Folder 4)
  - #799-813, 1965 March 27-1965 Dec. 24 (Folder 5)
  - #814-834, 1966 Jan. 21-1967 Sept. 20 (Folder 6)
  - #835-857, 1967 Oct. 20-1969 Aug. 20 (Folder 7)
  - #858-876, 1969 Sept. 20-1971 April 20 (Folder 8)
  - #877-892, 1971 May 20-1972 Aug. 20 (Folder 9)
- OPERATIONAL FILE, 1940-1974
  - General, c. 1950-1960 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1974
    - General, 1952-1973. Announcements to subscribers, and samples of bills (Folder 2)
    - Alphabetical, 1940-1973
      - A-E, 1940-1973. Includes: Courtney, W.B., 1941; Desverine, R.E., 1941-1946 (Folder 3)
      - F-J, 1941-1970. Includes: Hecht, Frank A., 1950; Hoving, Mrs. Walter, n.d. (Folder 4)
      - K-P, 1940-1959. Includes: Livingston, Goodhue, 1958-1959; Love, J. Spencer, 1946-1950; Pew, J. Howard, 1950 (Folder 5)
      - Q-T, 1940-1972. Includes: Snyder, Donald B., 1941; Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1940; Rosenstiel, Lewis S., 1940 (Folder 6)
      - U-Z, 1940-1958. Includes: Talbott, Mrs. Harold E., 1940; Williams, C. Dickerman, c. 1958 (Folder 7)
    - Libraries, 1941-1972 (Folder 8)
    - Organizational subscriptions and purchase orders, 1940-1952. Includes: (Folder 9)
      - American Jewish Congress, 1942
      - Japanese Embassy, 1941
      - Marshall Field & Co., 1952
      - Newsweek, 1940-1941
      - Standard Oil of New Jersey, 1941-1942
      - Time, Inc., 1941
      - U.S. Military Intelligence Service, 1941-1942
      - U.S. Steel Corporation, 1940-1941
    - Staff
      - Harvey, Marjorie Prescott, 1969-1974 (Folder 10)
      - Russell, Elizabeth Quigley, 1957-1960
        - Correspondence (Folder 11)
          - n.d.
          - 1958-1960
        - Statements for services, 1957 Feb. 23-1958 June 2 (Folder 12)
  - Financial materials, 1956-1974
    - General statements, 1956-1972 (Folder 13)
    - Bank statements, cancelled checks, and check register
      - 1969 Nov.-1971 Oct. (Folder 14)
      - 1971 Nov.-1974 Jan. (Folder 15)
  - Promotional materials, c. 1941-1952 (Folder 16)
  - Solicitation lists, c. 1946-1953
    - General (Folder 17-18)
    - c. 1946 (Resumption of publication) (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
    - 1946 March 30-May 22 (Folder 3)
    - 1946 May 23-Oct. 5 (Folder 4)
    - 1946 Nov. 2-1947 March 29 (Folder 5)
    - c. 1952 (Folder 6)
    - c. 1953 (Folder 7)
  - Subscription lists - date given indicates origin of record, and corresponds, when possible, to the date given by the originator. Dates given in parantheses are the inclusive dates of the records. All handwritten except when otherwise indicated.
    - n.d. (Folder 8-9)
    - Weekly Foreign Letter list, c. 1939-1942 (Folder 10)
    - 1946
      - A-M (1946-1947) (Folder 11)
      - Mc-Z (1946-1947) (Folder 12)
    - 1946
      - A-I (1946-1948) (Folder 13)
      - J-Z (1946-1948) (Folder 14)
    - 1947
      - Cards (Folder 15)
      - Ledger book, 1947-1950. Includes some office accounts. (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Lists (Folder 2)
      - A-M (1947-1951) (Folder 3)
      - Mc-Z (1947-1951) (Folder 4)
    - 1948
      - General (Folder 5)
      - A-Mc (1946-1949) (Folder 6)
      - N-Z (1946-1949) (Folder 7)
    - 1949 (Folder 8)
    - 1951
      - Ledger book, 1951 Jan.-Dec. (Folder 9)
      - List, 1951-1952. Typed (Folder 10)
    - 1952
      - General (Folder 11)
      - A-Z (1952-1953) (Folder 12)
      - A-Z (1952-1954) Typed (Folder 13)
    - 1953. Ledger book, 1953-1955 (Folder 14)
    - 1956 (Box 21)
      - General (Folder 1)
      - A-H (1956-1960) (Folder 2)
      - I-Q (1956-1960) (Folder 3)
      - R-Z (1956-1960) (Folder 4)
    - 1957
      - Ledger book, 1957-1972. Includes some office accounts. (Folder 5)
      - List, 1956-1959. Typed (Folder 6)
    - 1958. List. Typed (Folder 7)
    - 1959
      - A-J (1959-1972) Typed (Folder 8)
      - K-Z (1959-1972) Typed (Folder 9)
  - Renewals
    - 1946 Sept. 28-1947 May 31 (Folder 10)
    - 1947 June-1948 June (Folder 11)
    - 1948 July-1949 May (Folder 12)
    - 1949 June 4-Dec. (Folder 13)
    - 1950 (1950-1951) (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - 1951 (1951-1952) (Folder 2)
    - 1952 (1952-1953) (Folder 3)
    - 1953 (1953-1954) (Folder 4)
    - 1953 May 30-Dec. 26 (1953-1954) (Folder 5)
    - 1954 (1954-1955) (Folder 6)
    - 1955 (1955-1956) (Folder 7)
    - 1956 (1956-1957) (Folder 8)
    - 1957 (1957-1958) (Folder 9)
    - 1958 (1958-1959) (Folder 10)
    - 1959 (1959-1960) (Folder 11)
    - 1959 (1959-1973) (Folder 12)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1925-1974
  - Barton, Bruce. Newspaper column, 1951-1954. Clippings (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Collins, Seward Bishop. Biographical statement., Typescript carbon copy (Folder 14)
  - Communism and anti-communism (Folder 15)
    - General
    - Clark, Fred G. and Rimanoczy, Richard S., What Marxism Promises, U.S. Capitalism Delivers, 1956 Nov. Authors quote Lawrence Dennis. Pamphlet published by the American Economic Association. Also reprint of condensed verson from Reader's Digest, 1957 Feb.
  - Dulles, John Foster. Martin, James J., Meditations Upon the Early Wisdom of John Foster Dulles, 1958. Printed pamphlet. (Folder 16)
  - Economics (Box 23)
    - General. Angas, L.L.B. (Major)
      - General (Folder 1)
      - The Dollar, War Finance, and Your Pocket, 1951. Printed pamphlet.
      - Newsletter, untitled
        - #340, 1957 Oct.
        - #355, 1959
        - #372, n.d.
        - #393, 1962 Aug.
        - #456, n.d.
        - #499-a, 1970 Dec.
        - #501, 1971 May
    - Government
      - Fiscal policy and responsibility. Bober, W.C., The New Protectionism: What Will it Lead to? 1972 Aug. 4. Mimeographed statement. (Folder 2)
      - Free trade and protectionism (Folder 3)
        - General
        - LeBoutillier, Philip, The Responsibility of the Government in Monetary Affairs, 1949 Sept. 8. Speech presented at Economist's National Committee on Monetary Policy. Printed transcript.
    - Income (Folder 4)
      - Clark, F.G. and Rimanoczy, R.S., Who Gets How Much for Doing What in America? c. 1957. Clipping, with notes by Lawrence Dennis.
      - Graigen, R.F., The Big Payoff, c. 1954. Mimeographed pamphlet.
      - Thompson, Joseph S., A Basic Income, c. 1964. Printed pamphlet.
    - Taxation (Folder 5)
      - Schwulst, Earl B., The Problem of a Tax Cut, 1963 Oct. 8. Speech given at Mortgage Bankers Association Conference. Printed pamphlet with inscription to Lawrence Dennis.
      - Walinsky, Louis J., Taxes: When and Where? 1951 Feb. 12. Clipping
  - Fascism and anti-fascism, 1939-1971
    - Great Britain. Extract from Parliamentary Debates, 1943. Typescript carbon copy (Folder 6)
    - United States
      - General. Printed material
        - General. Clippings, 1939-1955 (Folder 7)
        - Gross, Bertram M., Friendly Fascism: A Model for America. Social Policy, 1970 Nov.-Dec. Clipping. SEE ALSO: Correspondence/Alphabetical/Individual/Gross, Bertram M. (Folder 8)
        - Pelley, William Dudley. Since When Was This Sedition! 1942. Flyer printed by the Justice for Pelley Committee, Noblesville, Indiana
        - Viereck, George Sylvester. Statement Before Sentence, 1943 July 31. Printed flyer
      - Dennis, Lawrence. SEE: Subject file/Isolationism and historical revisionism/Doenecke, Justus D. and Ribuffo, Leo P.
      - Hart, Merwin K. Biographical statement. Printed pamphlet, 1953. (Folder 9)
      - Sedition trial, 1944-1947
        - Clippings, 1944-1945 (Folder 10)
        - Correspondence(SEE ALSO: Correspondence/Alphabetical/Individual/Baldwin, Roger; Hays, Arthur; St. George, Maximilian) (Folder 11)
          - Unidentified, 1944 Jan. 19
          - Finerty, John F., 1944 Jan. 7
          - Hurley, C. Keefe
            - 1944 Jan. 20
            - 1944 Jan. 29
          - Morosini, Emil, Jr., 1945 Jan. 16
          - Rogge, O.J.
            - 1943 Oct. 17
            - 1944 Jan. 27
          - Stone, Leland A., 1944 Jan. 6
          - Sullivan, John H., 1946 Aug. 22
          - Welch, J.N.
            - 1944 Jan. 18
            - 1944 Jan. 19
        - Official documents. Briefs, memoranda, motions, opinions
          - Initial trial proceedings, 1944 (Folder 12)
          - Motions to dismiss or retry, 1946-1947 (Folder 13)
        - Trial transcripts, 1944-1947 (Folder 14)
        - Unofficial statements and reports, 1943- c. 1954 (Folder 15)
      - Stokes, Elizabeth Dilling, 1966. Obituary (Folder 16)
  - Flynn, John T. Printed archival register, University of Oregon, 1966. (Folder 17)
  - The Freeman. Serial issues (Folder 18)
    - Volume 22, Number 9, 1972 Sept.
    - Volume 22, Number 10, 1972 Oct.
  - Great Britain - History. British Information Services, Landmarks in Democracy, 1956. Printed pamphlet. (Folder 19)
  - Internal security, 1941-1955
    - General, 1943-1955 (Folder 20)
    - Military exclusion, 1943 (Folder 21)
    - Propaganda
      - General. Miller, Clyde R., What Everybody Should Know About Propaganda: How and Why it Works, 1952. Printed pamphlet published by the Commission for Propaganda Analysis, Methodist Federation for Social Action. (Folder 22)
    - Censorship, postal, 1941-1942. Correspondence regarding censorship of The Weekly Foreign Letter. Includes letter from Bernhard Knollenberg
    - Registration as a foreign agent, 1941 (Folder 23)
  - Isolationism and historical revisionism, c. 1944-1972
    - General
      - General (Folder 24)
      - Correspondence. (Between Dennis and students) (Folder 25)
        - Theile, Karl H., 1967
        - Williams, Ralph J., Jr., 1971
    - Barnes, Harry Elmer, 1950-1958. SEE ALSO: Correspondence/Alphabetical/Individual/Barnes, Harry Elmer
      - The Struggle Against the Historical Blackout, n.d. Printed copies of three different editions. (Folder 26)
      - The End of Old America. Modern Age, Vol. 2, No. 2, 1958 Spring. Reprint. (Folder 27)
      - Was Roosevelt Pushed into War by Popular Demand in 1941? 1950 Dec. 29. Discussion of a paper read by Prof. Dexter Perkins before the American Historical Association. Printed copy. (Folder 28)
    - Barton, Bruce, Are We Biting Off More than We Can Chew? Reader's Digest, 1948 Dec. Reprint. (Folder 29)
    - Doenecke, Just us D., 1972-1974 (Box 24)
      - Isolationists of the 1930s and 1940s: An Historiographical Essay. Georgia Studies in the Social Sciences, Vol. XIII, 1974 June. Photocopy. (Folder 1)
      - Lawrence Dennis: Revisionist of the Cold War. Wisconsin Magazine of History, Vol. 55, Summer 1972. Serial issue. SEE ALSO: Correspondence/Alphabetical/Individual/Doenecke, Justus D. (Folder 2)
    - Ribuffo, Leo P. Progressive Manque: Lawrence Dennis and The Coming American Fascism. c. 1967. Typescript report. Includes correspondence. (Folder 3)
    - Roseman, Herbert C., Revisionism and the American Crisis. Central Issues in Cooperative Adult Learning, Vol. 1, No. 8, 1968 June. Serial issue. SEE ALSO: Speeches and writings/Correspondence/Publishing companies (Folder 4)
  - Israel. Copies of clippings, 1970. (Folder 5)
  - Minorities, 1939-1967 (Folder 6)
    - Europe. Dean, Vera Micheles, Europe's Explosive Minorities. The New Republic, 1939 April 12. Clipping
    - United States
      - Asbury, Herbert. Who Is a Negro? Collier's 1946 Aug. 3
      - 150th Anniversary of the Birthday of Frederick Douglass. Congressional Record, 1967 Feb. 15. Reprinted by The Frederick Douglass Institute of Negro Arts and History, Warren M. Robbins, Director. SEE ALSO: Correspondence/Alphabetical/Individual/Robbins, Warren M.)
  - Miscellany, 1942-1968 (Folder 7)
  - Neill, Humphrey B., Neill Letters of Contrary Opinion, 1967-1971 (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1971
    - Mimeographed newsletters
      - 1967 May 24
      - 1970 March 25
      - 1971 Dec. 29
  - Peace Department, U.S. (proposed), 1969. Printed material. (Folder 9)
    - Clipping, 1969
    - Schuman, Frederick, Why a Department of Peace? 2nd ed., 1969. Printed pamphlet.
  - Public opinion. Poll results reported in the Congressional Record, 1955 April and June. Clipping (Folder 10)
  - Republican Party, 1942-1943. Typescript carbon copies of memoranda (Folder 11)
    - 1942 July 10. To Colby M. Chester from Claude Robinson, Re: the Republican Party.
    - 1942 Nov. 12. Regarding the Robinson Memorandum.
    - 1943, April 10. Third Memorandum on Republican Grand Strategy: 'Pamphleteering to Beat Roosevelt and the Fourth Term.' Second draft
  - United States - Foreign relations, 1925-1974
    - General
      - General (Folder 12)
        - General. Clippings
        - Armstrong, George W., The Marshall Plan Exposed, 1947. Reprint from World Empire, chapter XIX.
        - Gross, Bertram M., The New Atlantic-Pacific Empire. For CUNY seminar on The Planned Society. 1971 Nov. Photocopy of typescript draft.
        - Schuman, Frederick, The Neuroses of the Nations. Mimeographed typescript copy, n.d.
        - Zoll, Allen A., Should Americans Be Against World Government? Printed pamphlet published by the National Council for American Education.
    - Czechoslovakia, 1955. Expulsion of Sudeten Germans, c. 1945-1948. Congressional Record, 1955 April 25. (Folder 13)
    - Honduras, 1925. Correspondence: from Frank Kellogg to: (Folder 14)
      - Dennis, Lawrence, 1925 Nov. 17
      - Summerlin, George T., 1925 Dec. 22
    - Nicaragua, 1926-1974 (Folder 15)
      - Correspondence, 1926-1974
        - General, 1926-1927
          - Grew, Joseph C., 1926
          - Hanna, Matthew, E., 1926
          - Kellogg, Frank, 1927
        - Millett, Richard L., c. 1959-1967. Regarding research on American intervention in Nicaragua.
        - Ranta, Richard, 1972-1974. Regarding research on Nicaraguan crisis of 1926-1927
      - Printed material
        - Clippings, 1926-1931
        - Speech transcript. Wheeler, Burton K. to U.S. Senate, 1927 Jan. 26. Printed copy.
    - Russia-Cold War, 1946-1957. Printed material (Folder 16)
      - General
      - Geneva Conference, 1955
    - Venezuela, 1939 (Folder 17)
    - West Germany, 1955. Congressional Record, 1955 April 20. (Folder 18)
  - Utley, Freda, 1942-1969. Clippings (Folder 19)
  - Viereck, Peter, 1943. Biographical statement. Current Biography, 1943 April. Reprint. (Folder 20)
  - World War II
    - General, 1941-1955 (Folder 21)
    - Pearl Harbor (Folder 22)
      - General. Summary and syllabus for Amherst College course in which Dennis participated, c. 1953
      - Flynn, John T., The Truth About Pearl Harbor, 1944. Printed pamphlet. (Folder 23)
    - Yalta Conference, 1955. Clippings
- NOTES, n.d.
  - General (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Notebooks (Folder 25)
  - Index cards (Box 25)